Here we go.
What's going on?
Why are people writing what?
What's happening?
Do we have a... do we have an offender in the chat?
Who's the offender?
I who's being a bastard in the chat?
Let me turn that down a bit.
Oh, yeah.
Me?
How dare you?
Oh, man.
Yeah, we need to incorporate Jack into the Twitch live chat as well.
We got to let her dropkick some more people in here.
Not just the Discord, but also in the Twitch.
Oh, poll for challenges?
Well, guys, I promised last time that... next stream, massive speed.
I'm gonna... I'm gonna stick to that promise.
We're going speed today.
Speed, speed, speed, speed.
Maybe not all day, but a lot of it is gonna be speed.
Maximum speed.
Just like crisis.
Remember that guy going maximum speed or something like that.
I forget the actual words.
Maximum and then insert whatever, you know?
Guys, I'm feeling much better.
I wasn't really sick.
I was more... just my voice and my throat and my nose were acting up, so streaming was just out of the question.
So that sucks, because I really wanted to play both Red Dead and this game the last couple days.
But yeah, you know, it is what it is.
But I feel a lot better today.
I went to the... I went to the pharmacy and I got literally six different products to deal with it.
I got like tablets that I can dissolve in water to fix phlegm issues.
I got some kind of syrupy liquid that I need to drink that tastes like licorice.
I got nose thingies that sprays, nose sprays.
I got pills.
I got a whole fucking pharmacy at home now.
I even bought one of those freaking nose thingies like teacup or teapot thingies that you put in your nose.
I haven't tried it yet, but apparently that should work as well.
I don't know.
Yeah.
Exactly.
Pills.
They were doing so many pills today.
Last time was a drunk stream.
This is a stream while high.
Just kidding.
Don't forget, when we get to a million subs, we're gonna do a meth cooking stream.
With a camera, of course.
We're at 150,000 now, which is crazy by the way.
In a police office.
I don't know about that.
So excited.
Why are people just writing random numbers?
Will you be the Mr. White or the Jessie?
Probably Mr. White.
Guys, I am so ready for this.
We're going fast today.
Oh, yes.
Can you feel the speed?
Can you feel the wind in your hair?
Can you see how everything is getting shifted slightly blue?
Wait, let me not look at this thing.
Why do I always...
Dude, I need to find some kind of setup that works for this.
The current thing I have is not good.
Audio mixer.
There we go.
Found it.
Okay.
Coffee, check.
Mouse pad out of the way.
Check.
I'm ready.
There we go.
We're going online today.
We've got two other people coming in.
We're going to play co-op.
Nah, I'm not.
But we are doing speed runs.
The question though, oh my God, minus six win streak.
Kids, look away.
That ain't good.
Don't look at that.
That's horrible.
Maybe I will choose characters this time.
Because if I'm going fast... We also have this guy.
We have 19 Eden tokens.
You know what?
Why not?
Let's see.
I need to take off my watch.
Oh, speed is on.
We've got to go fast.
Hold on.
I can't get my watch off.
There we go.
Okay.
I think the game is actually not counting speed right now while I'm paused.
Okay, so what's the status?
We have spiky hair?
Mystery gift.
The gift is consumed to spawn a random pedestal item from the current room's item pool.
Chance to spawn the poop or a lump of coal instead.
Oh, wait a minute.
Wouldn't it make sense to use this in like a devil room?
Is that a free devil item then?
If I use it here, it's kind of bad, no?
Chance to spawn the booger tiers that stick to enemies and deal periodic.
Hey, I like that one.
Ex-lax.
Let's do it.
I mean, I'm going to go fast, but obviously it's going to be swift, but cautious, okay?
And both of those.
Got a bomb.
Nice.
This way.
And the booger seems to be quite frequent.
Both in game and real life.
So fitting.
More pills.
Okay.
Wait, we don't have time for that.
Treasure room first.
Treasure room.
Ooh.
I like that.
Yeah.
That's fun.
This one is one of my favorites.
I like it.
Dude, we can go fast now.
Look at all those hearts that spawn.
Kind of makes me want to step.
Dude, and with the with the bookers.
Oh, this is actually such a sick combo.
Wait, do my tiers go on forever?
Oh my God.
Wait, range is of no consequence right now.
I have infinite range.
Oh, I don't have a key.
Shit.
Man, okay.
Fine.
So far, so good, guys.
Let's be like I'm already killing it.
I feel so much better today than last time.
I am going to do so much better.
You'll see.
And it's not just an excuse for last time.
You know, like, I mean, it is an excuse for last time, but what I'm saying is it's a legit excuse.
Okay.
Pentagram.
Nice.
I like that.
You know, I'm just gonna use this gift here.
No, I'm gonna... Dude, let's go angel mode.
Angel mode.
And then we use a gift in there.
How about that, huh?
We got to go fast, though.
Let's go.
So that means we cannot do devils.
No demons for me.
Darkness.
That's fine.
I'm not afraid of the dark.
See, when we have this speed clear thingy item, we can definitely destroy those hoops.
It's not gonna cost us a lot of time.
Oh, shit.
Okay, that's fine.
I'm gonna grab that coin that I missed.
Oh, another chest.
No key, though.
There's a key.
I have a bomb.
Should I... I'm gonna exchange.
And I'm gonna save it for a potential treasure room.
Huh?
Oh, that was close.
Very close.
Okay.
This way.
The boogers.
Oh, here we go.
Immediately.
The Duke of Flies.
Please put on some boogers.
Oh, it's so good against the... Yeah, it's so good.
Mom's lipstick.
Range is useless on me.
So, whatever.
We got to find a treasure room, though.
Treasure room.
Dude, I really got to take a piss already.
What is wrong with me?
How is it possible?
I'm gonna do it soon.
We need speed right now.
Maybe that will egg me on to go faster, you know?
Nice.
Uh, familiar with the fire... Yeah, sure.
Whatever.
Okay, we're going a little slow here.
I really shouldn't be clearing this.
What am I doing?
We don't have time.
Okay, there's a shop, actually.
We have three coins.
That's not a lot.
No, we can't get in there.
Okay, we got five coins.
No key, though.
Let's go.
We're leaving.
Speed, speed, speed, speed.
This way.
Attempted to grab those pills, but I'm gonna resist the temptation.
Yeah, I'm not even gonna go in there.
Hey, look at that.
We got a present.
Just like this run.
Isn't that kind of funny?
Ooh, uh, library.
Nice.
I do enjoy.
Ow.
Oh my god, I just lost a bunch of angel.
Dude, what the fuck, man?
It's about taking damage.
Fuck.
Uh, no key, though.
Oh, I hate this room.
Oh, I was stuck.
Mistakes are being made here.
It was flawless up until this point.
I'll have you know.
Come on, booger.
There we go.
Uh, damage.
Yeah, that's good.
I'm just gonna use it now.
Why not?
We need speed.
Open up, sir.
Open that mouth of yours.
Okay, you're dead.
Good.
Oh man, no keys.
Oh, I have to remember, I don't need to charge this all the way up.
I can still shoot it when it's not fully charged.
In fact, that may be preferable against one enemy, because if I can hit with it, it's cool.
Good stuff.
Give me that key, damn it.
Nothing.
Dodge that.
There we go.
We got a key.
Treasure room.
I'm coming for you.
11.5% chance for, uh, for angel right now.
Let's try and pay attention to when that goes up again.
Bum friend collects coin pickups and occasionally pays up with pick a shirt.
I'm gonna try and steal most of the coins from him, though.
I'll allow some of them to go to his bank account.
Also, we need to go faster.
We're not fast enough.
Good.
Look at this place.
Here we go.
Wish me luck.
Wait, we lost more?
Oh my god.
Okay, so it's every time you take damage.
That's, that's pretty much just what it is.
I think we confirmed it.
Every time you take damage, you lose a chance to get, uh, angel.
Uh, squeezy tears.
Yeah.
And we go.
We have nothing else to do here.
No key to open the shop, so whatever.
We're ahead of the timer.
All right, let's go.
Dude, it's going so well right now.
It's nice.
Ah, I need a key so bad.
What is it with keys in this run?
I can't believe that.
Okay, good.
There's a potential for stepping, but we don't really have time.
Uh, angel, 72%.
We cannot take damage.
So I guess it's every, uh, floor you go to, it just increases.
And then when you take damage, it decreases.
But I guess the amount you get for, oh shit, we took damage.
Wait, we didn't lose any angel though.
Fuck.
Okay, now I'm confused.
Kill that thing.
Okay, kill that thing.
Good.
Oh, a key.
Huge.
Dark bomb.
So many bombs.
This is the one that picks up, uh, hearts, right?
Okay,
let's go this way.
Hearts, no thanks.
Oh wait, you, you, oh right.
He's gonna pick those up though.
That's good.
That's actually nice.
Open up.
I actually go back in here and let him pick those up.
Sick!
Thanks.
Two red hearts on command.
Still at 72% uh, angel.
Dead end.
No key to open that door.
Man, lack of keys is the, it's just the tagline for this run.
Are they gonna keep shooting?
Nice!
Good.
Boss acquired.
Carrion queen.
This guy's kind of tough actually.
Or gal, I should say.
Wait, no angel minus 72?
What happened?
I feel scammed.
I'm getting scammed.
What the fuck?
Okay, let's pay attention now.
What does the angel chance say?
We're also ahead of the timer still.
A hundred, okay, dude, I see.
A hundred percent.
Key, that's huge.
Another key.
Wow.
I'm not used to this amount of keys.
Oh, you bastard.
You bastard.
Oh, still a hundred percent.
So I guess after a certain floor, it's not about damage anymore.
It changes.
Nice.
Spiders, no.
Uh, I kind of want to get in there.
Yeah, we have five bombs.
Why not?
And one key.
Totally worth.
Oh, that's a friendly spider.
Wow.
Another key.
Nice.
Play it safe.
Point for me.
Got a big old room.
Abuse the fact that we can shoot through obstacles.
And the boss is here.
I'm just going straight in.
It's Gish.
I've never seen that.
That's a new boss.
Those bombs.
Okay.
I see.
I'm glad he doesn't shoot for Dectiles when he lands.
He does spawn bodies, it seems.
Careful now.
No problem.
What are you doing, son?
I can't touch the creep.
I'm scared.
Oh god, I have to... Oh wait, it's just slowing.
Okay.
Nice.
Little Gish has appeared.
Question mark?
Little Gish.
Sticky friend.
Familiar that fires slowing tears.
I have so many familiars right now.
Angel!
Uh, wait.
Spear of Destiny grants a spear melee weapon that deals contact damage to enemies.
And this familiar that grants a stacking tier bonus for each room cleared without taking damage.
Taking damage extinguishes.
I think this one is better.
I'm taking that.
Jesus juice.
Of course, that would be an angel effect.
I'm gonna bomb this guy.
Bring it on, sucker.
Check out my boogers!
Oh god.
Come on.
The boogers are doing massive work.
And you're dead.
Thank you.
I'll be seeing you later.
Guys, I gotta take a piss real bad.
I'll be back in like 30 seconds.
Okay.
Keep going.
We're still on the timer here.
Uh, maybe I'll quickly look for the treasure room.
Just quickly.
Let me see.
You can't be far off, right?
Come on, treasure room.
Man, what?
What's happening?
Oh, spiders spawned out of nowhere.
What the?
Oh, wait.
Ah, he's taking the hearts.
Right.
Last eye.
Sick.
More damage.
Oh, you bastard.
Next, come on.
Nice.
We got the key.
Come on, show me the treasure room.
Damn it.
Look at all my followers.
Well, that was not my intention.
Faster, faster.
Wait, where is it?
Am I losing my mind?
No, don't tell me it's in that little area I didn't explore.
The one freaking place.
Uh, wait, let me go in here also.
Horrible.
Oh, wait.
Wrong way.
Oh, man.
I'm spending way too much time.
Dude, here for sure though.
What?
Is it really in here?
Okay.
Uh, I don't know.
Apparently, there's no trick.
Don't tell me it's down here.
The last freaking place I didn't explore.
Come on.
Oh, my God.
It's actually here.
Oh, man.
That's so triggering.
We got a bunch of money though for something later.
Little Stephen?
Sure.
Let's go.
We're leaving.
We got, we have some catching up to do here.
We're also kind of low HP, but we have the lovers.
I'm gonna wait until we take one more piece of damage.
Look at my train of followers.
Okay, we're still ahead of a timer.
Not bad.
We got to go fast now though.
Faster than usual.
I'm gonna blow you.
I don't have time to barter with you.
Thanks.
Focus.
Well, that ain't good.
It's the chance you take.
Oh, wait.
The bomb guy.
I got to let him get the money, actually.
Okay, okay.
Wow, what a room.
It's okay.
Weird.
Okay, pick him up.
Pick him up.
Quick.
Nice.
Thanks.
I should have let him pick that up.
Oh, we have a store here.
Nice.
We get the range back.
I'll be buying this.
I'll be taking this.
Sure.
Give me that.
Leaving.
No, donate the rest.
Quick.
There we go.
Faster, faster, faster.
Okay, dude.
Pick it up.
Nothing for me?
Okay.
Oi, oi, oi.
That was a little bit risky.
Speed, speed, speed.
Okay, here we go.
Here we go.
Mom, let's do this.
I tried to be cute there with the bomb.
It did not pay off.
Got to focus now.
Nice.
Good shit.
Uh, move on.
Go.
Very good.
Boom one.
Actually, triggering my followers to shoot is not triggering his shots, so that would be one way to deal with them in a very safe manner.
Fuck.
See ya.
I'm scared of that bomb following me.
Oh, dice.
Three.
Wait, wait, wait, hold on.
What is three?
Uh, we don't know what it is.
Let's do it.
VRP?
What happened?
Rain shot?
Did I make something happen here?
Nothing changed there.
I'm not sure.
No idea what just happened.
Let's try and pay attention to what's going on now.
Kill them.
Oh, wait, I see, I see, hold on.
Something's wrong.
What's going on?
Oh, fuck.
Sorry.
My bad, my bad.
I just see this fucking flashing to the left of me.
My bad, guys.
I think that was only there for like 30 seconds or so.
You didn't miss much.
Just me being an awesome gamer.
You should have seen the way I cleared that room.
It was nuts.
Dude, I need some HP here.
I'm actually kind of running on fumes.
It's not looking good.
I'm getting in here.
What was the chariot?
Invincible speed.
Okay.
Give me some healing.
Where's my healing at?
Oh, no.
Wait, what?
Restock?
Wait, why is this happening?
Upon purchasing a shop item, a new item immediately takes its place.
I mean, okay.
No more shops though, right?
Also, are we still like... I didn't even pay attention to the timer before.
I'm not sure what's happening.
Maybe we're too late on whatever.
Dude, give me healing.
There we go.
A bit of healing.
That's huge.
I need more though.
Up here.
Crap.
Kill him.
Oh, man.
Secret room here.
Dude, I think speed run dreams are over.
I really think so.
Look for secret rooms.
Oh, shit!
I did not see that.
I did not even see that at all.
I was looking at the walls.
Oh, shit.
What a way to end.
That's unfortunate, man.
I want to unlock Jacob.
I don't know how to do that, man.
Or this one, which looks like a piece of cake.
I mean, not in the sense of difficulty, but literally looks like a piece of cake that I would like to eat.
I don't know what's happening with that.
Honestly, let's do Eden again.
I like that.
I think it's kind of fun not knowing what you start with.
And it's like spiky hair again.
Boomerang hits for 2x, I6 damage, petrifies enemies, and Jesus Juice and a pill.
Hello, dude.
Whoa!
I am error.
Huh?
What the fuck is this?
Okay.
I don't know what's going on right now.
Uh-huh.
I'm just gonna press all the buttons.
Something crazy is probably gonna happen when we press all the buttons.
Oh my god, I didn't mean to.
I didn't mean to.
Oh, crap.
Okay, so far so good.
Golden poop!
Yay!
Make me rich, make me rich.
Ah, only the shitty coins.
My question now is, uh, are we gonna go to the next level?
Oh, that's fucked up.
That's fucked up.
Well, that's no good.
Nice.
Oh, dude, the boomerang is... recharge immediately!
Wow!
Okay, the boomerang is kind of sick.
Holy shit.
Petrifies as well.
Dude, the damage is really good on that.
Nice.
Jump at me.
I know you want to.
Give me that.
Ooh, that's a good one.
Ah, you bastard.
Actually, it doesn't matter.
Mitre.
Blessing of purity.
Which one was that?
Cancel converting red hearts into... I'm not a big fan of that.
Active.
But it's good when you have full HP, you know?
That is good.
Actually, I think it's good in general, because you find more red hearts than soul hearts anyway.
Yeah, all in all, good active.
Or like passive, I mean.
Dude, the boomerang!
Wow!
Wow.
It's no joke.
This may be one of the best actors in the whole game.
I don't like any of what I'm seeing.
Uh, actually, maybe the key.
Ah, we'll find the key.
We'll find the key.
Unfortunately, the boomerang does not destroy poops.
Here we go.
I'm gonna boomerang these assholes.
Yeah.
Oh, it doesn't get petrified the second time.
And he's dead.
I did it so well until that last sequence there.
Um, I'm good.
Go!
Okay, we gotta go faster and faster.
Dude, I'm lacking damage.
What would I do without the boomerang right now?
Oh my god.
Nice.
I'm actually gonna go in here.
Fuck it.
Worth just to explore.
Ah, I thought I could get past him.
I couldn't.
Dude, I lost so much demon.
Fuck, I... Okay, so you really cannot take damage, is what I'm learning here.
It's like one of the most important things.
It's very consistent.
I think the first three floors or so.
Dude, whoa!
Okay, we need a key.
Wow, I gotta get in there.
I need that.
What?
I thought you were stunned, you bastard!
That instant charge was crazy.
There's the key.
Are you ready, kids?
What are we gonna find?
Soul Radiant Victory displays the location of the boss room on the map.
After defeating the floor's boss, automatically activates the sun.
Tarot card effect fully recharges Isaac's active item, removes floor curses, and grants damage up and luck for the rest of the floor.
In other words, you want to kill the boss fast and then do the rest of the floor.
Got it.
That's cool.
Man, I love the music in those rooms.
Okay, the boomerang falls off like crazy.
It does not scale well.
Maybe it's only good for the petrification now.
The damage is pretty much negligible.
I mean, this was pretty clean.
Uh, oh, okay.
Oh, I see where the boss is.
We gotta go there.
It's good at clearing out the smaller guys.
Oh, I went the wrong way.
Yeah, well, if you stun someone in front of the others, they can't shoot through them.
That's interesting.
Sick.
That was masterfully done.
Mega man.
Okay, looks like there's an internal cooldown on how often they can get petrified.
Careful.
Wait.
Just kill him.
Nice.
The sun and cracker jacks.
We love the cracker jacks.
What's this?
Uh, Eve's bird foot.
Yeah, sure.
Secret room.
Wait, is that also discovered?
Oh, because of the sun, right?
Oh, man.
That's actually neat.
That's dope as hell.
We don't have time for that.
We gotta go.
I think we do have time for the shop.
No, the treasure room.
And then we go.
Fuck the shop.
Shop is next floor.
How am I missing everything with this freaking thing every time?
Crazy.
Knockout drops, chance to fire fish.
Oh, that was a fun.
That was a nice.
Okay, off we go.
Here, the way my character looks, I look like an enlightened, uh, I don't know, freedom and joyer.
Cheers.
100% demon.
Let's try and keep it that way, huh?
Wait, we're still at 100.
It's because we're on floor four or five.
So there's some other mechanism at play now.
I gotta figure out what it is.
Oh my goodness.
Kill the tomatoes.
Motherfucker.
No, wait, nevermind.
I lost my shit now.
I, maybe it's just random, you know?
There's a chance when you take damage.
It's like a pretty high one, though.
Whoop.
Careful.
Man, I have 2.12 damage.
I'm actually in the shitter.
I need to find damage and I need to find it now.
I need to find a brimstone right now.
Otherwise, this run is over.
I am tickling my enemies.
Why not?
I'll kill you.
Dry baby, why not?
I'll take that.
Okay.
Treasure room, shop, okay.
There's a heart here I could take.
Let's go.
Oh, we know what the boss is.
I have to remember this.
We gotta go for the boss first.
Shit.
This run is in the shitter.
I don't have time for this.
Come on.
I think we're way too far behind.
Unfortunately.
I just can't not take damage.
God fucking damn it.
Gertie, this is gonna take 10 million years.
Did my baby just stop his charge?
Oh, I'm gonna die.
Wow.
Man, this game is hard as fuck.
The healing helps, though.
Secret down there.
I'm grabbing that.
Useless.
Okay, moving on.
The problem is, even if we do make it speedrun style, we're not gonna be able to win shit with this damage.
Like, it's just... it's rip.
We are just simply limited by gear right now.
There's a gear check coming up and we don't have the gear.
Uh,
oh wait, these guys are immune.
Fuckin' hell, dude.
Insane room.
Oh, no.
Okay, that's gonna help me.
My bird is helping out quite a bit.
It's almost like the bird is doing more DPS than I am.
We gotta go for the boss immediately.
Oh, shit.
I'm in the wrong way.
This way.
This dry baby is really nice.
I guess it doesn't matter that I take damage.
I'm gonna be healing when I kill the boss.
Iron bar.
Damage up and Concussive Tears.
Okay, I need a damage up.
Uh, change increases with the lock.
Okay, sure.
But what about more damage up?
Nice.
Here we go.
Two hearts against Loki.
Oh, not the frickin' spiky boy.
I'm gonna blow him up.
Yeah, good.
Blow up the bomb.
Yes!
Very good.
Strategies here.
Huge!
Look at those strategies, baby.
Random pills.
You know I'd be eating those.
Health up.
Pretty fly.
Love it.
We're going in here.
Uh, I'm taking both.
Fuck it.
Give me that.
The Pact.
Use this.
I think I'm actually gonna keep going with my boomerang.
I need damage.
I just wanted to do this once.
And we get one out of Guppy.
One out of three in case we find more.
Uh, wait.
So, secret room is there.
Shop.
I think it's worth it to go back for that.
For those two things.
No, no, no.
We don't have time.
We gotta go.
We're ahead of the curve here.
Gotta be fast.
This room is not that hard.
It looks insane, but it's not that insane.
Okay.
Love when that procs.
Uh, the bomb is down in the right.
Okay, so it's probably this way then.
That's how it's gonna connect.
Is that range?
I don't need that.
Uh, no, I don't need that.
Nice.
Oh, right.
You gotta hit them from behind.
Good.
Ah, fuck.
Wrong way.
Actually, it's good.
Treasure room.
I was a bit lucky.
Come on.
What is it?
D10?
They've also...
Honestly, I think it's better than the... No, I need the boomerang, man.
I don't...
This is my damage.
This is what I need.
I need it.
This has to connect somehow.
I don't know why I ate that.
What did I eat that?
I saw what it was.
I was like, yeah, let me eat that.
I didn't say we were gonna eat pills today, right?
When I say I eat pills, I mean it, damn it.
Yes.
Down we go now.
Come here, you.
Faster.
Boomerang's gonna be good here against these guys.
God fucking damn it, dude.
Then we go down after this.
Motherfucker.
I'm losing all my HP.
Whoop-de-doo, you get nothing.
Sir, you lose.
Of course.
Give me that.
The moon.
After this boss.
After the boss.
Man, you cannot time that.
That is so difficult.
I think we are dead here.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
It's not that bad.
Yep, yep, yep.
We need more damage on mom.
Motherfucker.
Good.
It's actually good for keeping her in place and then attacking her.
The petrify, I mean.
Yeah, yeah.
Oi, that was a close one.
Okay, well, we did it.
Uh, get
that one.
Uh, fuck, I can't take a deal, man.
I feel like it's over.
I'm taking a deal.
Because it's over.
This is my only option.
We have to go, uh, balls to the wall or nothing, you know?
Oh, no.
The cold.
Moon.
A shop was up here.
That means we can make a shortcut.
I don't have time to go around.
What a nice assassination attempt there.
Fuck you.
No, I need items.
Don't do this to me.
Steam sale.
Great.
Really useful.
I was kidding.
It's actually horrible.
I also think we weren't fast enough.
I think that time is over.
The thing is supposed to open on this floor, no?
It's not the next one.
It's the one with mom.
So I think we're actually cooked.
Okay.
Next floor, we got the heart.
That was so close.
It's taken forever.
Guys, I think, I think we're cooked.
Like, even if I make it through this level, I have no damage, no HP.
It's, yeah.
I think it's over.
Yep.
I expected that.
It is what it is.
Okay, let's try another one.
So we did two different characters.
I want to go with maybe Samson, actually, or Kane.
Wait, Kane has paperclip now.
I remember unlocking that.
Let's try it.
Let's go with Kane.
I like Kane.
Lock chests can be opened without using a key.
Very nice.
Money equals power.
Let's see if we actually end up with a lot of money or not.
This is either very good or very bad.
But, like, we did an excess of money here.
We're going fast, by the way, of course.
As fast as we can.
All things considered.
This is one big old room, though, with a lot of enemies.
Also, we cannot take damage.
This is important.
We're going for angels.
Oh, we're definitely taking that.
Oh, okay.
Range is good.
So we got to go right and then down.
Weird room.
Nothing in there.
The spider is scaring me right now.
Jump towards me.
I just need him to be on my ass.
There we go.
Then I can predict his movement.
Dude, I have more damage on this character now than I did on my other character in the whole run.
How crazy is that?
Also, I just noticed we have sea represent demon on floor one.
I think it's always like that.
Thanks.
Yep.
Two of clops.
That's the bomb run, right?
Yeah.
You know what?
Is that a secret over there?
No.
Monstro.
I'm going to really lock in here.
Like, I can't lose any HP at any time.
Well, I guess right now is okay because I have sea represent demon, but I'm still going to lock in.
Just play it safe.
Like, move out of the way.
Don't be greedy.
Yes.
Solid.
We love it.
Tropicamide range and tier size.
We love that.
And we move on because we are on a timer.
Small peepee fell off.
Just run in circles.
Whoa.
Wow.
Just like that.
And a pill.
Okay.
Very good.
Wait, we didn't lose demon.
Lucky.
Bomb for me.
Is it worth it to do this?
Maybe not, right?
No, it's not worth it.
Don't you poop on me.
Okay, he was about to do it.
Oh my god.
Oh, I didn't lose again.
Oh, wait a minute.
Maybe it's only red hearts.
I gotta pay attention to that.
But wait a second.
We should do boss now.
We should go for the boss immediately.
Let's do it.
Larry, it's time for you to die.
And I'm going to hurry.
So can you please die fast?
I would appreciate that.
That was a bit risky.
Come here.
There's way too much poop.
Oh, fuck.
Yeah, look, still a heartless demon.
I think it is related to red hearts.
Come here.
Question mark.
Dissert.
Nice.
Dude, since we got the cert, should we go demon mode?
Hold on, we're on timer.
Yeah, let's go.
Fuck, I can't see what it is.
Nah.
I'm an idiot.
It's okay.
We're going to gamble.
It's going to be okay.
This one.
Dark matter.
I like it.
I keep that.
Moving on.
Eat the candy.
Feel bad.
Don't eat candy because there's a razor blade in there.
100... no, 33% demon.
You frickin' bet range, though, is unacceptable.
Charge me bastard.
Oh, nice.
Yo, the idea is to have like a buffer for the red hearts.
So you don't take red heart damage and get reduced deal chance.
This is actually the strategy.
Oh my god.
And this door opened.
Dude, I am getting lucky with this.
No pun intended.
Whoa.
Bring it on.
One more wave.
Oh, not these guys.
Okay, thankfully it's not laser.
Clean.
Absolutely clean.
I don't know why I did that.
I should have been just moving because we are in a hurry.
Was that a fly just now?
Dude.
God, I hate these enemies.
This is the most annoying room I've ever had in my life.
Die, motherfucker!
Jesus Christ, that took 20 years.
We don't have time for this.
Oh my.
Wow.
Holy.
I'm under assault.
Man.
Okay, treasure room detected.
Oh, you absolute piece of shit.
Spawning a skeleton immediately and immediately shooting the thing.
So evil.
Oh yeah.
I feel like this entire floor is insane.
Okay, that was a bad one.
Can't get lucky with all of them.
Whew.
Not the worst though.
Steven, again.
What is your deal anyway?
Just homing tears.
Okay.
I mean, that's cool.
Please don't laser me.
Kill him, Steven.
No,
no, no, no, no.
Fuck off, stupid flies.
Okay, okay, so check it out now.
We are at red HP now.
Sure, why not?
Just use that.
If we take damage, we should be losing a chance.
Wait, these flies are actually fucking with me.
Kill him, kill him, kill him.
Oh my god.
Run has been saved.
Hellthot baby.
Oh, and a million money as well.
We need a shop.
And there's the shop.
Very nice.
In fact, all this money, I could also save it for the money equals power, right?
Triggered the game kit effect when taking damage.
No, I would rather have that, I think.
Starter.
Oh, actually, buying this heart is actually worth as the buffer.
We're doing buffer.
Yeah, I'll be back for the starter deck, I guess, if I get enough money.
The buffer strategies have begun.
All right, give me this.
Good thing I had the buffer.
Okay, that was a bomb.
Key over there.
I'm gonna grab that.
14 coins.
Can we get one more coin?
There we go.
I'm gonna go back and grab that item.
Jira.
Wait, wait, I'm actually confused.
What is this?
Can I hold two cards at once?
All future pill drops are replaced with cars, spawns a random card.
I mean, that's good.
That's fine.
I like it.
Okay, we gotta be careful now.
I cannot stand on the green shit.
He's gonna start flying across the screen soon.
I'm gonna be ready for that.
My damage is decent.
Dude, I would love to just damage this guy, but he has so many minions.
I gotta focus him a little bit.
Get off your horse.
He's gonna start flying now, or...
Maybe I'm confusing this guy with another boss.
Nice.
A cube of meat.
Sure.
No room for me, though, unfortunately.
But it's fine.
We're not doing too great with the speedrun here.
In fact, I kind of forgot about the speedrun a little bit.
I gotta be honest.
A little while ago, I totally forgot.
Oh, shit.
No.
Wealth of wealth is actually good for us because of money equals power.
More money is good.
The tower.
Why not?
I can have two things at the same time.
If I find some nice health, I'm gonna Jared that.
This room is a nightmare.
It's the stuff of nightmare.
Okay, let's go here.
I was trying to look for secrets.
Very good.
Very solid.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Look at this!
Jupiter!
You're a gas giant.
Nice.
Plus two health?
Whoa!
More speed?
When standing still, Isaac rapidly gains a speed increase of up to 0.5.
Moving expense this bonus while spawning fart clouds that poison enemies.
Makes Isaac immune to poison gas spawned by enemies.
Lovely.
Oh my god, I'm actually fat as hell.
Yo, that's awesome.
I like it.
Big fan of that.
That's cool.
I just don't like that I'm fat because I'm easier to hit now.
You need to die.
Oh, you bastard.
Where's the enemies?
Hello?
Oh, there you are.
Oh wait, I have no money.
Oh, nice.
Blood bombs, plus one health, heals four red hearts.
How many scores does one of those allows placing bouncing bombs?
Ooh.
Oh, okay.
That's interesting.
I'll be taking that.
Actually, dude, we got to do this.
We got to get a buffer.
Buffer time.
Oh, man.
Too bad.
Come near me.
I got gas for you.
Hahaha.
No.
Oh, yeah, look, we lost demon mode now.
It's confirmed.
I'm gonna write that down.
Losing red health, loss of demon.
It is confirmed now.
Oh, stop losing health again.
Ah, wait a minute.
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
Interesting.
Second time, no loss.
This is the same line.
I'm just gonna do that.
I'm gonna have to revamp those notes a little bit in the future.
Okay, go this way.
I need you to come near me.
I got gas for you.
Get poisoned, nerd!
That's for you.
Uh, what's that?
Mom's foot?
Okay.
Why did I go in here?
Oh, we can maybe afford that.
Yes, we can.
Keep moving.
I
really love the gas giant.
Oh, that's a big guy right there.
I thought I was the gas giant here.
This is the type of solar system I can get behind.
I'm gonna stand still for a bit just to make farting noises.
Are you gonna come over here, sir?
Okay, fine.
I'll come to you.
No.
Okay.
Missing page two, black card.
Yeah, sure.
I'm fine with that.
Uh, yeah, we're done here.
Move on.
Man, we are so far behind the timer.
I don't think we can actually make it.
Unless I somehow stumble.
Uh, we can't even see where we are right now.
We gotta somehow stumble on... on the boss room now.
Like, real fast.
Oh, shit.
I'm in danger.
I'm gonna be so lost.
Lots of farts.
The farts are actually good.
Uh, got no money.
Fuck.
Uh, telescope lens increases chance of planetarium.
Yeah, sure.
I don't know how the fuck people dodge these guys.
Like, it's... it's... for me, impossible.
When you're in a small room like that and there's four or five of them,
you can't stop me from taking the chest.
There's someone else.
There you are.
You can see the butt of this guy when he walks.
Look.
God, I hate not having a map.
It's actually driving me crazy.
It's probably the worst curse.
Here's the boss, though.
I don't think we're in time.
Cube of meat.
I'm just going.
I'm going.
Fuck it.
We're moving.
Okay, at least we can see the map now.
I'm kind of stuck in the center here.
Walk into my farts.
Pawn's a beggar?
Why not?
Judgment.
Treasure.
What is that?
Charm of the vampire.
He's half a red heart for every...
Hey, huge.
Very nice.
I like that.
The farts are going to be my main source of damage, I think.
Fuck off.
Okay.
Lucky penny.
Ow.
Man, I need some HP here.
We got buffers now, but a little too late for that.
Could have used Jira on that, but I feel like I need to save Jira for at least two.
I can't use it on just one.
It feels bad, you know?
Destroy that.
No, I walked on the crab.
Why did I walk on the crab?
Wow, that was lucky.
Can you jump to me?
Okay, good.
Need more healing.
Wouldn't mind those enemies that spawn a bunch of tiny spider thingies.
They can trigger the healing.
Oh, I should have used it there.
Fuck.
That was a bit too fast.
I think these enemies are also in my top five most annoying enemies.
I pushed the bomb away!
I will never hit that bomb, ever.
It's just not allowed.
Yo, I'm going to stand still and make farts for mom.
As soon as she jumps at me, I'm going to fart her up.
Yeah.
Actually, a really good strategy.
I have the human sprinkler.
And we heal up.
Nice.
Now we fart up and then we start farting everywhere.
Oh, there we go.
Keep healing.
Ah, you bastard.
Oh, she did it twice in a row.
I'll take that.
I feel like this run has been underwhelming in a lot of different ways.
I almost haven't gotten any demon deals or angels or anything.
It's been tough.
Okay.
I shall get in there.
Wait, I didn't need to use a key there, actually.
Oh, I forgot to look at the time.
Were we ahead of it or... Oh, no.
Dude, this guy's fast shooting.
What the fuck?
How are you dodging that crap?
Wow!
That's like impossible.
I think we're dead.
I think it's over, boys.
We got to heal from some of these kills.
There we go.
That's something.
No problem.
Oh, we're going to get some healing here.
We can do it.
Oh, sick.
I don't want that.
Huge healing.
Oh, we're so back.
We are back, baby, with the underwear as well.
I am so happy right now.
That's what we needed.
Destroy this.
That was unnecessary.
Maybe unnecessary.
That's what I was about to say.
Where do we go now?
What's up?
Oh, yeah.
Oh, man.
The farts coming in clutch here.
Man, fuck these eyes.
I swear to God.
Go!
Loki!
What's up, Loki?
I'm going to sprinkle her a little bit here.
Man, they're really avoiding my gas.
And gas.
Fuck.
Tears and fire rate.
Okay.
I guess that's okay.
Dude, I'm just not getting any of the good stuff here at all.
I want to go heal.
Thank you.
Let's keep moving.
Down we go.
Maybe I was too fat to fit in the hole.
You to row two.
I'm going to run into my farts here and it's going to be glorious.
Oh, my God.
What is this?
Jesus.
Okay.
Wow.
Oh, we're going to heal in here.
This is going to be good.
Walk into my farts.
These rooms are actually insane for when you have...
I don't know which item I have that gives me that, but, you know, the healing.
Let's deploy some farts now.
And here's the boss.
That's kind of lucky.
Oh, God.
Oh, these fucking eyes.
There's one more.
Okay.
Okay, here we go.
I'm going to... I'm going to fart a little bit.
Lots of farts.
Okay.
Not bad.
We're going down this time.
I've had enough of going up.
We're going down.
I have the ultimate strategy.
The magic number right now is 18.
That's all I'll say.
Come to me.
I got farts.
This guy wants money, eh?
No, money equals power.
I can't do it, son.
What's that?
Cheers up.
Oh, wait.
Oh, this is the room to do it, guys.
This is it.
We're going to wait.
Just in case there's more happening.
Oh, my God.
You bastard.
Wow, he mad.
He real mad.
Dude, this guy's crazy.
Fucking hell.
Jesus.
Well, now we need to find some healing for red hearts.
Okay.
That's one.
Not bad.
Farts for y'all.
Ooh, that's exciting.
Let's see what it is.
Well, why?
Oh, this is crazy.
Oh, it's Jera again.
Okay.
We're going to save it for at least two soul hearts once again.
Dude, I was moving.
How did he hit me?
So, it's actually impossible to dodge or what?
Like, I was moving at full speed.
Oh, oh.
Oh, no.
Teleport to the shop.
Why not?
Oh, okay.
Wow.
Well, there goes my blue hearts.
It was nice knowing you.
There's one more.
Saving the Jera, though.
We got to find a room with blue fires.
We got the bombs for it.
Oh, there we go.
Amazing.
Jera.
Man, I don't know how you don't take damage in these levels.
It's fucking crazy.
I'm just not skilled enough to dodge that, man.
It's too much.
I need a buffer of health for every single one of these rooms.
I got Farts for y'all.
Oh, yeah, that's nice.
That was a lot of healing.
Very good.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
I'm going to fart it up.
Any item?
Okay.
The question is, though, can we beat the boss?
This is the big one.
I think we have the capabilities with the bombs here.
Wait, this is awkward.
Okay.
I'm going to need a little bit more healing.
Oh, my God.
What is this?
Wow.
Oh, shit.
Jesus.
What a room.
Okay, I think we're just going.
Push me lock.
I'm going to bomb him.
Oh, what a start.
Perfectly timed.
Actually insane.
Fuck you.
That's for you.
Here comes the foot, I think.
No, first he does that right.
Oh, no.
Shit.
Okay, here it comes.
I'm going to fart it up a little bit first.
Keep bombing.
Yeah, yeah, I did it.
Oh, my God.
Fuckin' hell.
I thought I lost for some reason.
Okay, it's the same one.
The bomb bag has appeared.
The negative has appeared.
Cool.
What do I do now?
Win streak one.
It's the start of a new day, baby.
Okay, guys, we got to get it to...
We got to get it to two.
And the only way to guarantee it right now is to take a Seizel.
A Seizel run.
We got to take it to two.
Speed.
Full speed.
No slowing down.
We're going for two.
Look at him lining up for me.
Optimization.
Nice.
What do I get?
Money equals power again.
Let's find some money, then.
Go south.
Dude, getting a win in this game is so invigorating.
It's crazy.
Hey, range up.
We love that.
How did that guy just die up there?
Give me me.
And you're dead.
Give me that.
And we're moving.
Speed, speed, speed.
Oh, we have the full as well.
Let's not forget.
Oh, wait, we can fly.
Right, so we can actually get to all kinds of places.
I almost forgot I could do that.
You got to get used to how broken a Seizel is as soon as you get on him.
Like, oh, yeah, I can do all those things.
Just ignore this room.
The world?
Why not?
That sounds fun.
Wait a minute.
On a Seizel, if you don't find a red heart, I wonder if you have like just way better chance of getting the deals, then.
Because you don't have any red hearts to take damage to, you know?
Ah, another common W for a Seizel.
Are we surprised at this point?
I'm not.
What's that?
Tears and spectra, but I already have that.
So that's pretty much useless for me.
Nice bombs.
I need that.
Huge.
Dude, I'm actually gonna... No, I'm not.
Yes, I am.
No, I'm not.
Keep moving.
What?
Oh, we have curse of whatever right now.
Curse of confusion.
Who else wants some?
You.
Boss is up here.
Let's go.
Wow.
Go.
We dove.
You're gonna keep jumping like a maniac.
I know how you work.
Man, I can't hit.
Dude, this boss is actually so annoying.
I feel like the hitbox is hard to know where it is.
On that boss.
Fuck you.
Ah, yes.
I'm taking deal.
Oh, there is no deal.
Okay.
Shot speed down.
That doesn't matter for me.
I'm not gonna do it again, though.
Shit.
No!
What's that?
Charge at the fire's up to... No!
Absolutely not.
I think... Oh, wait.
I actually want to grab this.
We are done here.
Move.
I believe east.
Take care of the threat before they evolve.
This door opens, so we use it.
Dude, if you want to super optimize, you can even wait with looting anything until you get a Jira.
And if you don't get a Jira, then you take it all.
But this is like some next-level penny-pinching.
You know?
Or penny-pinching.
You know what I mean.
Thank you.
And we'll see what's in here.
Underwear.
Range is so good for me.
Wow.
Definitely destroying poops now.
Look at that money.
Huge.
Dude, my freaking hand is itchy.
What's wrong with my hand?
Money!
Dude, we need to shop now.
Shot speed down.
No, thanks.
What's going here?
Mega fatty.
No problem.
Health?
Angel!
Whoa!
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Trini's shield block shot's not... I don't know what that is.
Oh, that stigmata is so good, though, but I gotta take this.
I need to see what it is.
Eclipsed by the moon.
Orbital familiar that multiplies each tier that passes through it into four tiers in an...
arc?
Wait, really?
That's cool.
It's a prism.
Very neat.
I dig that.
You like rainbows?
Here's some rainbows for you.
Rainbows?
Oh my god.
Massive.
Thanks.
I'm not done here.
I need myself a shop right now.
We are pretty far ahead of the timer, I think, so we're good.
Fucker!
I can't believe he did that.
Virgo, if you refresh and protect this.
Chance will take damage to activate a shield.
Chance increases with luck.
Converse negative.
Oh, yes!
We're gonna be pilling it.
Love the pills.
One of my favorite things in this game.
And there we go.
Shot speed, though, is unfortunately not very good on me.
The prism effect is so damn dope.
How did I miss?
There's the shop.
That's what I'm here for.
Ah, come on, wake up, wake up!
Thank you.
Buddy in a boss, grands are falling familiar with the randomized appearance, fire rate, damage, bonus, tear effects.
Come here, traits are randomized.
Yeah, sure.
I'll take that.
I'll take the pill as well.
I can sick forever.
Very nice.
That's useless, though.
Wait, another secret was revealed just now?
Oh, where?
Oh, here.
No way.
Didn't do much, though.
Okay, we gotta move.
We don't have time.
Bosses all the way in the bottom right.
Go.
I'm gonna need a bit more HP here.
I feel like I'm not quite happy with my HP.
Go, go, go!
Okay, we're barely ahead of the timer.
We gotta hustle now.
This is embarrassingly slow.
We may even skip something on this floor just to go faster.
Ah, you freaking bastard!
Nice!
Door closed?
Sure.
Nobody knows why.
It's a mystery.
Getting rich?
Oh, that was sick.
I should have known this wasn't the room.
Shoot pen!
Chance of fire slowing shot?
Incredible block?
Yeah, why not?
That's combat focused.
The other one was poop focused.
No way.
Oh, prize bombs!
Okay, chance for bombs to drop a pickup or trinket?
Chance decreases by one percent for each detonation.
Chance resets each floor.
Yeah, charm random enemies.
Dude, sick.
That sounds pretty good.
Not a big fan of this here, though.
I was hoping I could buy something.
Dude, nice.
Again.
But we don't have time to start looking for secrets.
Maybe on the way back, it's probably going to reveal something as we go.
Uh, bosses this way, I think.
There we go.
I'll blow that up.
I'm gonna take bombs.
I feel like I'm not fast enough.
Go, go, go.
Let me spend my money.
Secret.
Oh, I like this.
We're actually gonna go ham here.
I'm going full.
Full send on this.
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
Where's my soul hearts at?
Faster.
Ah, whatever.
I don't want to spend all of my money.
I gotta retain some damage.
I was hoping with some soul hearts.
I didn't get a single.
Like, what are the chances of that?
Oh man, oh man, oh man, oh man.
That was not worth it.
Blood oath.
Uh, I hate this item.
Why did I take it?
Wait, I thought this was the active.
I mean, it's fine.
We don't really need red hearts, right?
Missing page two, little brimstone.
That's two out of three unconjoined.
Could be worth it.
Black heart deals room.
I take this.
Let's go, let's go.
Moving, moving, moving.
Now we're gonna be at one red heart.
Yeah.
Shouldn't have picked that up.
Massive regrets.
Maybe we can get some blue hearts here.
I'm lucky.
There's one.
That's something.
Guys, we're doing it!
Health up!
Let me see what we get here.
Shooting continuously in one direction gradually increases fire rate up to a 2x increase.
Okay, but that's not gonna help me, I think.
This bonus is reset each time Isaac stops firing and fires in a different direction.
Jesus juice, crickets head.
A lot of damage!
Wow!
Consolation prize.
Papa fly!
Fly familiar that follows Isaac's movements on a delay.
Fires once per second with Isaac's tear damage.
Toothpicks, blood oath, bomb bag, familiar that drops a bomb, pick up every three rooms, okay.
Steam sail, one equals power, we retain that.
Active contrition, that's new.
Plus one eternal heart, but we didn't get that.
Allows angel rooms to appear even if a devil deal has been taken.
And then we have spirit of the night.
Okay, well.
That's cool, I guess.
More damage.
I like it.
I was just feeling it, you know.
Gigante beam.
Uh, size of Isaac's farce.
I don't care about that.
Oh my god, blue hearts galore.
More health up.
Holy shit, brother man.
Love me some pills.
Oh yeah.
Pills are the best.
Not bad at all.
Uh, I'm not gonna go in there.
What about this poop?
Like, okay, it darkens the room, but what does that mean?
Flush.
Hey, I like that one.
Wait, I need to understand something.
Something about my tears.
Oh no way.
Okay, so my follow up is going to charge faster.
Oh, it is good on me then.
I see how it works.
That's cool.
I dig that.
Show me the good stuff.
That's a lot of money.
The more the better, the more damage we get.
Huge.
Scary.
We're not fast enough.
Flush him.
No, wait, where is the boss?
Why is it always the last place I go, man?
Here we go.
The gate.
Can I flush you?
No.
I want to get dingle.
That's 100% what you need to do.
I want to flush that poop so bad.
Angels.
Oh, this thing.
Uh, sure.
Oh, dude, we're gonna have a fight in here.
I was trying to hit both though.
Fight me.
Fight me, nerd.
Nice.
I'm gonna take that as well.
Give me that.
We move on.
Go.
Let's see the timer.
Okay, we gotta hurry.
We gotta hustle now.
Straight to mom.
Let's go.
Speed.
Speed, speed, speed, speed, speed, speed, speed, speed, speed, blow them all up.
Let's go.
Give me that.
Reveal the map.
Sure.
Mom is here.
That's cool.
Let me
move on.
Oh, wait.
The map.
This way.
I see.
Come on.
This way.
Range up.
What's this?
Pretty fly.
That's fine.
Whatever.
Flush him.
Flush the poops.
Speed, speed, speed, speed, speed.
Bot fly.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Go, go, go, go, go, go.
Speed.
Get flushed, nerd.
I shouldn't have flushed because it's harder to see the shadow on the floor when it's flushed in here.
Nice.
Oh,
the negative.
Fate chosen.
Damage.
Taking damage with half or less red hearts will trigger a mass damaging effect.
Allows access to deeper stages.
Can be used to open.
What?
Okay, but we got a good in here.
Let me see what we got.
I don't know what that is.
That's new.
Sulfuric acid.
Yes, mother.
Wait a minute.
A fungi.
Wait, what's this?
It has to fire a fungi shot that stick to enemies when attack, fungi shots grow to a certain size.
That's good, actually.
I want to try this.
Halo of Flies.
Grants two pretty fly orbital familiars.
Hey!
Beals above three out of three!
Whatever that means.
We're the fly master now.
Come on, bitches.
I'm so ready for you.
Next.
Where are you?
Oh, there you are.
Come on, dude.
We need more speed.
This ain't fast enough.
Oh my god, I can't see where he is.
Okay, we got him.
We got him.
Pop out.
Uh, you need to die now.
You're gonna go up north?
Yeah.
Oh, you're dead already.
Okay.
Dude, my damage is pretty fucking good right now.
I have 18 damage.
This guy just got beamed up by Scottie.
What the hell is that?
You're dead.
Okay, good damage here.
An angel!
I'm not afraid of you.
Dude, I'm unstoppable right now.
I should not jinx it.
King Sing is a mistake.
Oh, where did you come from?
12 out of 15.
Okay, there you are.
Got troll bombs.
That's scary.
Good.
What the hell is that?
Pass!
Frees all enemies in the current room for up to 30 seconds.
Jeez, that's good.
That's like really good.
Also, I forgot to flush this room.
Okay, we got to hurry though.
We may still be on a timer here.
In fact, what is the time?
2350.
Go.
Okay, let's go.
Oh, what the fuck was that?
Oh, right.
It's the sacrificial thingy.
True.
Strength is nice.
Here.
Thanks.
Oh, that's good.
Oh, I thought it was the entire map.
That's not the same.
It's still good though.
Puberty.
wouldn't cross as one holy shield at the start of each floor.
Oh, nice.
I like that.
Very nice.
Another secret room.
Curse of the Lost?
Yeah, no thanks.
Lockdown?
No thanks.
That's okay.
Yeah, well.
That was a shit room in terms of pills there.
Wow.
That was just a smorgasbord of crap.
Let's go.
We got lucky here with the boss.
Dada Toma.
Dada Toma dead.
Give me back that hell.
Give me back that health.
Honestly, I go.
We move.
Speed.
I don't need, like, I am already good in terms of items.
Oh, right.
We take damage.
I have to remember that.
And you're dead.
This room is disgusting looking.
Okay, we don't have time.
Oh, god.
Oh, we had the holy shield.
Nice.
I just blocked that.
Go, go, go, go, go.
Speed, speed, speed, speed, speed.
Oh, cool.
Wait, that didn't last very long.
Oh, wait, they got friendly.
Here we go.
Hey, eyes are gone?
No, wait, not yet.
One more.
Oh, that was clean as hell.
Oh, you're dead, son.
Holy shit, the damage.
Oh, okay.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
There's multiple things.
Let's go in here.
Uh, wait.
No, the devil is gone.
Fuck.
I should have gone there first.
God damn it.
Shit, I was like, oh, do I go in there first or do I go here first?
Because last time it disappeared.
Oh, yeah, right, we take damage.
Let's see what we get here.
Two of Clops doubles bombs.
That's a lot of bombs now.
I'm definitely doing okay on bombs.
Oh, shit.
The first enemy killed in each room explodes and poisons nearby enemies.
The wiz.
Isaac fires two tiers at once, but it's... I don't like that.
Oh, it could be good, though, honestly.
But I think I like this more.
Yeah.
I don't want to have to relearn everything now.
Chance to apply that bullshit or... No, this one.
And then we have... Wait, question marks?
Can I... Oh, yeah, right.
Okay.
I buy that, of course.
Converter!
A little too late, though.
Convert.
Thank you.
Oh, wait, no, no.
Here.
Battery.
Convert.
Grab that.
And we're gonna grab this one.
Okay.
That was Isaac's coins.
Wow.
That's a lot of extra damage we just gave there, guys.
Holy shit.
Time to donate some money.
We don't need all that damage.
We're gonna donate until this breaks.
There we go.
Beautiful.
I'm gonna blow this guy up.
All right.
Here we go.
Wish me luck.
Man, I want to try and bomb him, but I guess it's not worth it.
My damage is pretty good as it is, right?
Here we go.
Dude, this guy is tanky AF.
Ah, fuck.
Oh, god.
I'm trying to do the bomb maneuvers.
I keep fucking it up.
This guy is so freaking tanky.
Holy shit.
It's a bomb for you.
That was well timed.
Okay, it's kind of risky being up here.
Oh, my god.
What the shit?
Oh, he mad now.
He mad now.
Kill the little guys.
Dude, these flies are fucking MVPs right now.
They're saving me so hard.
Oh, this is a good spot.
This is a good spot.
Yeah.
Oh, wait.
What?
Wait, why do I have?
Whoa, hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on.
Right, I came from here.
Dude.
Yes.
The void.
Oh, shit.
Oh.
Oh, my god, my HP.
We're fucked.
Hey, you want money?
Give me some hearts, will you?
Come on.
I'm going to give him all my money if that's what I need to do.
Door is opened.
Could it be here?
Maybe I'm approaching the door.
Come on.
Okay, sure.
Not exactly what I needed, though.
I needed healing, but thanks.
Okay, give me that.
I'm scared.
Just a bit.
A second door?
Maybe that doesn't matter the second time.
I'm going to start looking for secrets.
I'm an idiot.
I see the secrets.
Not bad.
And you're dead.
Oh, here.
Last tears.
Decreases max health.
Turns into a health uphill if Isaac has one heart or fewer.
Bean!
Fucking liar!
You mean your liar!
I had one health or fewer, you idiot!
What the fuck!
I swear to god, dude.
Fucking liar.
That's not true at all.
I thought I was going to get fully healed there.
Telepills.
I'm so mad right now, man.
Shit.
Wait, the boss?
Hold on a minute.
I'm not ready for that.
Kidding?
No way.
Oh god.
What the fuck?
Kill that thing!
Oh wait, there's bosses everywhere.
Oh, this is some bullshit.
I don't think we're long for this world, guys.
This may be the end.
We'll have to see how it goes.
Oh, what the shit is this?
Pause it!
That didn't do much.
That didn't do anything in fact.
Where's the other guy?
Oh, healing.
Massive.
Okay.
Lockypenny.
I'm going to go for the secret room.
Should be... wait, what?
I don't... wait, what?
I don't know where that secret room is here.
That's confusing.
Here?
What the frick?
Ah, here we go, here we go.
I see.
The layout confused me.
Uh, oh, you can have keys.
You took my good key!
Uh, distant admiration.
Distant overall fly that deals... yeah, sure.
I don't need the good key anyway.
I had two of them, right?
I mean, this is not even that bad.
This floor is fucking easy.
Hello?
What is this?
Easy.
Oh, what?
This looks cool!
Dude, this guy's fast.
Man, that pause is literally useless.
It pauses for a millisecond.
That's huge.
Any hearts at this stage is important.
I'm not even questioning these otherworldly looking areas right now.
It is what it is, you know?
There was a red fire there, I didn't see that.
Unfortunate things happened.
Okay, more damage.
Hold on, I gotta blow my nose.
Let's do this.
Oh!
Trying to throw pause at me!
That is just not okay.
Nah, I keep this.
No!
What was that one?
Hasn't updated yet.
There we go.
Familius orbit around Isaac.
Wait.
Uh, I don't know if that's good or not.
I don't think that matters.
That's probably the same for me right now.
Give me some healing.
Dude, there's pauses everywhere.
I'm scared of this.
Shit.
Give me some healing.
There we go.
Flies.
Chest.
What the hell was that little guy?
You saw that?
That was weird looking.
I think it may be time we just start killing some things.
I wonder how this works.
Delirium!
Oh wait, this is the guy I lost to.
Uh-oh.
I may or may not be in trouble.
Whoosh.
Oh, that's actually kind of nice.
Dude, it stopped all the projectiles.
That's kind of huge.
Gotta focus here.
It's probably the end, but I'm gonna do my best.
We gotta just give the flies time to deflect here.
This is the main thing.
What the shit is going on?
Oh no.
Kill the little guys.
This guy's changing shape, left and right.
Wow.
Okay, be careful.
Nice.
These flies are working overtime.
We gotta give them a raise.
This is very nice.
Careful.
Avoid him.
There was a bomb on him.
He keeps jumping.
I'm in big, I'm in big shit here.
Keep trouble.
I think it's over.
We got spiders everywhere and shit.
Almost died to it.
Oh, yeah, there it is.
Oh, man.
I, this is crazy.
So what, I gotta do...
What, six or seven of these bosses on this floor?
That's fucking wild!
Oh, oh, oh.
Okay, let's change up the character now.
That was fun, though.
That was a fantastic run.
Uh, let's do...
Let me think.
Dude, Cain is actually super fun.
I like Cain a lot.
Magdalene...
is the very hardy one.
Isig is solid with the d6.
Uh, Bethany...
What is that?
Oh, I'm not a big fan of her playstyle.
I gotta be honest.
I don't like it very much.
I don't like the idea of merging the items and no.
It's not really something I enjoy too much.
Let's go with Eden.
You never know what you're gonna get.
Boom!
Remote detonator?
Detonates all place the bombs, while held bombs do not detonate on an automatic timer.
And Jacob's ladder.
Electrify's tears, causing them to emit damaging sparks on impact.
Sparks can change to multiple enemies.
Okay?
Cool.
That sounds really good.
Dude, I am slow, though.
I am... You know who I am?
I'm Electroboom!
Actually!
You know the guy from YouTube?
Ha ha ha ha ha!
That's who I am!
Holy shit!
It is so...
fitting!
Dude, can you please die?
Thank you.
Dead bird?
That's an Eve item?
Uh... don't care about the shop right now.
Okay.
We gotta go fast.
I'm too slow.
Oh yeah, the chaining here is... is real.
Huge!
Nine coins now?
We could be going for the shop, I think.
Dude, this is really good.
This item is fantastic.
Jacob's ladder.
Low him up!
Solid.
I could also save my money for the next floor.
Pin.
Dude, I have nine bombs.
I really should be using those.
Ah, so wait, how do I blow it up again?
Ah, shit.
Okay, it's space.
I thought I just clicked the same button again.
Sick.
Booster pack.
Hey, that's nice.
Two soul hearts.
That's nice.
Two damage.
Two of hearts.
It's just two of hearts.
Doubles, I6.
Whatever.
Plus two damage.
Plus one health.
Use this.
Wow, hitting the flames also sparks... or arcs to the enemies.
That's nice.
Oh no.
Good thing we had a key.
Out of keys now, though.
Speedrunning is going to be pretty hard when you can't speedrun.
But I'm going to do my best.
I think the arc is going to be a huge deal in the speedrun.
Okay, we go right.
Oh wait, give me this.
I'll use that for a bit, why not?
Honestly, not even a bad use there.
That room was crazy.
I will say, though, my damage is really low.
I may have the arcing, but...
Yeah, damn, my damage isn't very good.
It doesn't feel good, at least.
Um, this way.
Actually, I should be taking this.
Oh right, eye control.
Wow, just one guy in here.
Fuck you.
Okay, there's the boss.
We're going.
Widow.
Good night.
Oh, that's huge!
In that case, we're definitely...
Uh, no thanks.
That's not very... then again.
Nah, that's horrible.
I'd rather be without.
What an actually shitty item that you have to spend health to get.
Thanks.
So good.
Jacob's ladder, man.
I lost demon!
Oh, but, oh, wait.
Did the door just close?
And then it opened again?
Hold on, is it when I pick up a blue heart?
Or maybe when I have a blue heart?
Wait a minute.
Dice or fight room.
Need blue heart?
To enter?
Because I just didn't have a blue heart.
It closed, now I had one, it opened.
Uh, plus 3 coin.
Yeah, sure.
Wait, is it going to arc between...
Oi!
Nice.
Too bad it doesn't arc between the shits.
That would be glorious.
I'm not actually going to go in the fight room, because we're on a timer.
I know I haven't been going very fast, but I'm trying.
Faster!
Money me.
I actually kind of like boom.
Big bada boom.
I can't get in there, that's so sad.
Uh, yes.
Spiderbot, baby!
There we go!
Love that item.
We're cooking.
Oh, it's so nice.
I can see where the enemies are clearly now.
And there we are!
Going in!
We're going to blow them up.
Asshole.
No.
Oh, I got no more bombs, shit.
Oh, you're not dead.
Squeezy.
Ooh, nice.
That's some more buffer there.
Uh, uh, go!
Let's see the timer, let's see the timer.
Okay, we're ahead of the timer.
Something I want to do is try to actually look at the in-game time elapsed.
And try to pay attention.
So we currently are at almost eight minutes.
Okay.
We're going to try and look towards the end and see if we can notice a pattern.
Dude, having Spider-mod against these guys is especially good.
So you know which ones are going to explode.
Oh, fuck off!
Dude!
I'm getting tilted!
The tilt is real!
Don't tilt now.
Of all times.
Open up, open up.
What just hit me?
God, these cars are just...
Oh, I feel so good.
Oh, that's beautiful.
Oh, that's my friend.
Okay, what have we got?
Uh, let me guess.
This is the glaucoma?
No, it's the eyesore.
Okay.
Uh, sure.
Whatever.
Oh, that's actually really good with electricity, dude!
Extra shots randomly?
It's going to arc randomly, right?
Ooh!
My friend!
Convert!
We're going all in, baby!
This run, we can't lose.
We actually can't lose.
It was on sale as well.
Even better.
Oh, fuck up!
Why am I playing so shit now?
I'm running into fires and stuff.
Just not a good time.
Kind of want to go back to the shop and buy more things.
Hop up.
And there's the boss.
Let's do this.
It's good!
This is actually a tough one.
Yeah, I'm going to take a lot of damage here, I can tell you right now.
I just don't know how to dodge against this.
I'm too slow, man.
That's fine, though.
We don't need to dodge.
Ah, that's huge.
The speed is going to help us so badly.
Because I was slow as hell.
We're ahead of the timer.
Oh, convert.
And we heal!
It's so good.
The only downside to a converter right now is you lose the buffer, right?
But then you pick something like this up and you gain the buffer.
So actually, everything's cool.
I don't mind having this, I think.
Up to four uncollected pickups from the previous floor respawned.
Ah, bullshit.
Don't care about that.
Oi, yo, yo.
Nice.
This way.
We gotta blow them up.
This bastard in the center just had to get that hidden!
Like a little...
When I walked by, you know?
Just a little slap in the face.
Wait, is it arcing off the...
It's arcing off rocks!
I'm telling you.
This arc is insane.
Okay, we don't want to go in there.
Wow, this item just gets better and better.
I'm gonna go in here, though.
The arc is off.
Oh, I forgot to convert my black heart.
That's sad.
Oh, I can't get there.
Arge off the stones!
Yo, this is sick!
Oh, I love it.
So nice.
No keys, though.
Oh, man, actually, no keys?
That's kinda bad.
Oh, well, that had to happen.
It's actually a speedrun strategy.
Get hit, and let them die faster, right?
Gimme that key, man!
I need a key right now.
There we go.
I got it.
Found a boss, as well.
Uh, do we go shop or treasure, though?
I think shop is better here.
We have so much money.
Uh, bombs?
Yeah.
Ah!
Keep me.
Yeah!
Nice.
Wrap that.
I'm actually gonna donate.
It's about time that we donated some money to that.
Let me go in here.
Ooh!
Amazing!
I like those.
So the boss was up here.
Convert.
27% angel chance.
The arcing is gonna take care of the ass.
Mostly.
That's for you.
Toothpicks.
Uh, nothing.
We go.
Unfortunately, no angels.
We're ahead of the timer.
Let's see the in-game timer.
It is, uh, 14 minutes, okay?
Arcade, that's not good for me.
Uh, okay, so check it out.
No blue hearts.
Door's closed.
I'm gonna try and come back with a blue heart if I remember and I have time.
Wait, does this arcing scale with my damage?
Uh...
It doesn't look like it's...
Maybe.
Oh, I'm so scared of those little stone dudes.
That's so sad.
I wonder if the orange or the purple ones actually spawn blue hearts as well.
Uh, blow them up.
Even though we're gonna have bombs in here now.
Old capacitor has appeared.
See ya!
There,
I love the ark!
J cup, j cup, j cup.
But the problem is we're gonna have trouble finding the boss and we're lost.
Ahoy!
They call me the needle-threader.
And the trendsetter.
I'm the trendsetter!
As Flea said.
Famously.
I'm gonna go north.
See, this right here is what we call a PROBLEM!
Yep.
I don't know, oh wait, I have an idea.
I go in there and I push the bomb away.
Ah!
Go in the corner?
Genius!
I'm a genius!
See, that was not smart, the way I just wasted one of those corners.
Nice!
Oh god!
Convert!
Almost forgot.
So we're approaching the stage soon where we're gonna stop converting.
I would say probably, maybe even now, maybe one more convert and then we're done.
Then it's time to pick up another active.
This is the optimized gameplay.
Bro, will you stop pooping on the floor?
Door stop, keeps it...
That, you know what, that is actually not bad.
I actually like the idea behind that.
Blow that up.
One more convert and I think we're done with converting now.
Now I'm looking for a new active.
Mom!
How's it going?
Having a good day?
Careful, careful.
Ah, that was bad.
Focus.
Wait, who hit me?
Easy.
Ah, oh, I just realized.
Dude, Polaroid and the negative.
It's just inverted colors, I guess.
It's a negative, makes sense.
So, taking damage with... oh, oh, let's also check time.
1827.
How about you wanna bet?
The cutoff is 20 minutes.
Okay, .98 damage.
Taking damage with half of less red hearts will trigger a mass damaging effect.
That was actually the deeper stages.
Okay, we know what that is.
Can be used to open a strange door, though.
That's the big one, right?
I'm gonna go in here.
Oh, I need that.
Satanic Bible?
Uh, ooh, that's really good, dude!
That's really... dude, I'm taking that.
Dark bomb, I don't care about you.
Fuck you.
Gimme that.
We're gonna go in here.
Let's see what we got in here.
Minecrafter?
Sister Maggie, familiar that fires tiers for 6 damage?
Each tier Isaac fires gains a random color.
That could be good if that actually spreads with the arc to everyone.
I don't know if that's gonna synergize like that.
Let's try it.
It kinda looks like it does, based on the colors.
Oh, fuck.
This guy does lasers.
Oh my god, stop!
Jesus.
This guy won't stop.
I think this is gonna be a tough one, guys.
I don't know if I have the damage for this.
I don't have flying either, so creep is gonna be a problem.
I think... I would say 50-50 that I can even do this.
I gotta be real here.
Unless they keep dropping hearts for me, then I'm good.
There's a heart there.
This guy's gonna keep jumping like a maniac.
The black hole, though, is good.
Very good.
No, I ran into that.
Dude, the black hole and the arc is an Archon Toilet!
The ultimate Archon Toilet!
It's sick.
I don't like those red poops being here.
Making me nervous.
Okay, this is feeling good, man.
I feel good.
Dodge that.
Okay.
Let's see what you got.
At least you throw bombs.
Black hole, good!
Arcing time!
Get a black heart.
That was an insane dodge just now.
I'm proud of myself.
Black hole!
Get him out of here.
Angels?
I think the angel is the most dangerous one.
Okay,
yeah, black hole.
Oh, the arc is gonna be sick here.
Against all these little guys.
Chain Lightning, baby.
Palpatine mode, engaged.
Dude, this book is so good!
This book is made for this.
Get that damage in there.
Here comes the puke.
I need more tears.
Oi, oi, oi, okay.
This guy we're gonna wait with.
Nice.
Kill the little guy first.
Nice!
Wait, this guy can only shoot down or something?
Aww, bastard.
Dude, we're killing it.
I was like 50-50?
Haha, right.
I was wrong about that.
I see that now.
Dude, that battery is actually sick.
I wanna kill the devil first here.
What the hell is happening?
Wow, he's tanky.
Ouch.
Now, where's that other guy I saw?
Undefined has appeared!
What?
Spelunker Hat reveals the map.
Propped to two rooms away.
That's cool.
Sure.
Not bad.
Hey, you're not even dead.
Okay, we gotta go.
Gimme that.
Let's go.
So now it's gonna be a random boss and then we have the heart.
Aww, we're lost.
No.
My room detector is useless now.
So I started here, let's go right.
I'm gonna try and keep a mental map of the layout.
Dude, that battery?
It's a small one.
Okay, fine.
No, never mind, I don't have a key.
Kinda crazy that I don't have a key.
A fucking spawn right in front of me, man!
Did you see that?
I think that was a single frame of it spawning.
Crazy.
Okay, not bad, not bad.
No, no, no, don't blow me up!
Oh, shit.
Bastard!
Fuck these rooms.
Totally horrible situation here.
It's actually so sad.
Gimme!
Kinda wish I had a converter again now.
Kill him.
God, I love the spider mods so much.
It's just such valuable information that it provides for me.
We're gonna be wandering very lost for a while here.
Oh no, am I back here?
I'm actually gonna go around.
Get away from me.
I'm too scared of that room.
There's fucking statues, man.
Probably one of the hardest enemies in the game.
The immobile statues that just go...
hardest foe.
Dude, my damage is really cool, though.
Feels nice.
But I want more.
No, thanks.
Dude, where is this boss?
Oh, that's exciting.
Except I can't.
Yes, I can.
No, I can't.
I can't.
Oh, wait, no keys.
Oh, shit.
Those eyes are impossible to dodge.
I think you need a certain move speed to even dodge that.
Oh, man, gimme a key!
Shit!
Fuck you all!
30 long legs.
We meet again.
My friend.
He's gonna keep moving.
Oh, he was charmed.
That's funny.
Oh, I figured out how to deal with him.
Oh, crap.
Definitely not my best moment here, but, you know, it's okay.
Moving on.
Ah, I hate the hearts.
I have really good, like, AOE damage, but my single target is terrible.
I'm scared.
I knew that was gonna happen.
Secret room spotted, too.
I don't think I'm gonna have enough damage for the things I wanna do.
Come on.
I have to remember that I can shoot the rocks.
And have it arc from there.
Like this.
Like, it is actually massive that it could do that.
Oh, wait, that was a secret back here.
I need, uh, money equals power right now.
That's what I need.
Oh, god.
Man, what?!
What's hitting me?!
Is it the flames?
I can't even see those things, man.
Oh, that's good.
More damage.
I need more like that.
Telep- Oh, treasure room, if not planetarium.
Ah, shit.
So, I guess we sort of confirmed there's no planetarium.
That sucks.
Oops.
Wrong way.
What's that?
Troll bombs?
Why not?
Here we go!
Kill the eyes!
Huge!
Nice!
We thought it.
We diddly thought it.
Now we're just gonna dodge this.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kill the little guy!
Good!
Huge damage!
Very nice!
And we got this as well.
I'm not terribly excited about all this.
Maybe Guppy's paw?
Multidimensional...
Let me see if I have to pass through it.
Doubled and gained increased range and shot speed.
For me, with the arc, could be actually sick.
I'm taking that.
I think we can make something happen with that.
If done right.
So, here we're gonna...
go down.
We're going down.
I need to find a bit more damage and then...
if we can make use of this baby now...
we could potentially have the damage we need.
Okay, that's good.
Only five or four hearts though.
That's kinda questionable, isn't it?
We gotta start saving up these black hearts.
You just have them done, of course.
Oh my god.
Like, for example there, you know, I couldn't really go anywhere.
No, thank you.
Oh, thank you.
I'm good, bro.
Let's go down here.
No, stop picking that up!
Motherfucker!
Hate that.
Blue hearts.
No, I have no more bombs!
No way!
I need it for the secret room!
I have troll bombs, though.
Let's use that.
Spawn's a beggar, why not?
I don't have time.
I want this.
These inanimate fucking objects are ruining my run.
Good.
No bombs, oh my god.
There we go, that's one.
I'm gonna use that to get into the secret room.
Should be here.
Yes.
Oh god.
What a shitty secret room!
Okay.
Experimental pain.
That's fine.
I didn't mean to do that, actually.
Oh, actually, you know what?
What?
How is that real?
That's crazy.
Oi!
We're going.
Where's Milak?
No bombs, though, so it's gonna be a tough one.
We're gonna have to have good play here.
Oh, wow!
Fuck me!
I think we're done.
Yeah, we're done, we're done.
There is no way.
Yeah, take me out.
Take me out to the shed and fuck me up.
Oh, that was a fun run, though, I will say.
That was a fun run.
Let's do a challenge to finish it off.
I like that.
I wanna do...
Oh, I really wanna unlock eight.
But I guess I can do Demoman.
With Wesley Snipes.
Okay.
So we have boom, got it.
And feed... oh!
No kidding.
All right.
I love that already.
Dude, this is gonna be easy.
Am I crazy?
This challenge is not gonna be a challenge.
I'm calling that right now.
Advanced tactics being employed here.
Dude, I paused that.
We're doing the slow and calculated route now.
No reason to go speed, I guess.
This is a challenge.
I love that stuff.
Getting all those at the same time.
Dude, I'm just picking up bombs left and right here.
It's almost as if I need more bombs.
I don't.
Thanks.
What was that one?
Glowing hourglass.
Reminds time and places Isaac in the previous room on doing everything that occurred in the room after three uses that uses the hourglass.
That is actually kind of...
Whoops.
I didn't mean to do that.
That's actually kind of a crazy item.
You can...
If you're really deliberate, you can probably make good use of that, you know?
Hey!
That's right, we gotta look for secrets because I can just destroy everything.
You know what?
Hell yeah, this is how I'm gonna finance my items.
Locky penny!
I love that.
Thanks!
That means we can grab the blue heart as well.
This is a good time.
I'll be taking that.
Like, who needs boom when you already have bombs?
That's just overkill.
Ooh, I really want that, actually.
I fucked up.
We need to get more HP and donate more so we can get that instead.
Or not instead, it's actually complementary.
It's not inactive.
Yeah, we're chilling.
Let's go in here.
Oh, we have already been there.
Let me read this thing again.
Reminds time and places Isaac in the previous room undoing everything that occurred in the room.
After three uses.
Instead uses the...
I forgot what the hourglass effect was.
But, yeah.
Oh shit!
Right.
Almost forgot that I had bombs there for shots.
Nice.
Keep them coming.
What about this?
Where's the other secret room?
And let's not get roped into thinking that we have a treasure room because we don't.
There's no treasure room.
Dude, will you die, please?
Uh...
Like, why would I want to find more bombs?
No, thanks.
I'd rather have the poop.
Definitely destroying all the mushrooms.
What makes you...
Yeah!
Huge.
I mean, small.
Okay.
I'm in trouble!
Maybe.
Nothing there.
Oh god.
Are you gonna...
Wow.
Let's go south.
Okay, this room is suspicious.
Like, what was that room?
Okay.
Nice.
I need four coins more.
It should be doable, right?
Sometimes you find crazy things in these rocks.
Not today, though.
What about from in here?
Man, am I really gonna go home without that belt?
That feels terrible.
Wait a minute.
I just had an idea.
What if I go into a room, eat a pill?
It's a bad pill I reset?
I wonder if the pill is reset?
Or if it's, like, changing?
Can I scope out the pills?
Huh.
Son, come here.
Wish I had the flusher right now.
No!
How did I get hit by that?
Embarrassing.
Hey, dinner.
That's good.
It was a fake boss.
Honestly, that's good.
More chance of getting pennies.
Goddammit.
Huge.
Magic eight ball.
Chance of planetariums.
I love planetariums.
I want more of those.
And more damage for the room.
Why not?
Twelve coins, though?
Hold on.
I'm going to go into the room where I take damage.
Because I'm going to get some money.
I need three more coins.
Yeah!
Three more coins!
Exactly what a man needs!
Insanity!
Oh, wait.
This is the wrong way.
No, it's not.
Yes, it is.
Wait, I also had this room to check.
Oh, my God.
Oh, hey!
That room is even more crazy now.
Because of that.
Oh.
That's my bomb.
Thanks!
Very cool.
And now we move on.
What a first floor.
Or was it second?
That was the second, okay.
Wait, notice there's still a timer?
We're going speed now.
We convert to speed.
We're doing it.
You're dead.
Oh, shit.
Okay, so check it out.
Okay, tears up.
Fine.
We're going to experiment when...
Oh, we got to go fast, though.
Faster, faster, faster.
Oh, what is this?
Dude, this is insanity.
Jesus Christ.
Good night.
Wait, let me check something.
Heart coin.
Ooh, it's the same.
Okay.
Dude, that's actually...
Yo, you can make some crazy place with this.
There you are.
Didn't mean to blow that guy up, but that's okay.
The devil.
Thanks.
I should be doing this.
Ah, we're going fast.
We don't have time.
No, not this.
Bro, I hate this so much.
I don't think that's fun at all.
That's just bullshit.
Oh, my God.
How are you not dying?
We're actually rich.
Why am I getting bombs?
I don't need those.
Okay.
You know what?
Let me see.
Mom's bracelet.
No, I don't like that.
Oh, they're actives.
I was just about to reset the room, but actually I'm going to save it.
Bad gas.
Okay, I don't want that.
Whoa.
Sick.
Go here.
No, not this bullshit again.
Okay.
Nope.
No, thanks.
So now we do it again.
I swear to God, these flies are...
Get
the fuck away from me.
Yeah, see, now I'm not going to take the pill.
Wait, which pill was it?
Fuck.
I'm not resetting again.
We're leaving it.
I don't want to fight those flies again.
I'm going to lose my mind.
Oh my God.
The flies have completely tilted me.
Like, I can't even play straight anymore.
Go.
Pestilons?
Are you dead?
Devil time.
I have the occult damage range, less shot speed.
Oh, I don't like that for this.
No, no, no.
No, thanks.
Give me a chance to drop a soul heart when I say...
That's pretty good.
And we have one lock as well.
Oh, you bastard.
Okay, well.
That's fine.
That's totally worth.
I also have some healing back here.
I'm going to grab real quick.
I think we're pretty much...
done for in terms of speedrun here.
But it's okay.
The main objective is to do the challenge, right?
Yeah, we're behind.
Okay, so if we assume the 20 minutes...
Let me see what it is now.
12, okay.
Nice.
What is that?
Three random cards.
A bagger?
Sure, blow him up.
Plus two damage, the devil...
I like this one more.
Oh, dude, I can get that.
No, I can't.
Damn.
But check this out.
We're going to do this.
Oh, that's a shit room.
I don't like it.
We go back.
Actually crazy.
Just kill him, please.
It's like playing pool.
Perfect split.
Lucky two.
More luck, it's good.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, the sun.
Wow.
One thing I will say though, we need more HP.
HP is the problem right now.
Good.
Yes, let's go left.
Well, we are rich.
I can buy anything.
Minus one range.
Placebo triggers the effect of the pill health.
I'll buy a key actually.
Maybe this one too.
Yeah, I'm good.
I'm good.
No, my God.
Insanity.
He's going to die so fast.
Come on, clean.
Yeah.
Oh, that's a good one.
Yeah, massive.
Very good.
Let's go.
That took us a while.
I don't think we can actually catch up to this timer unless we find a boss real fast now.
I would love to do a quick one here.
I think up is the right way to go.
No.
Wait, what the hell is all that?
Please.
Nice.
Crazy key as well.
Oh, that takes me here.
Shoot pen, chance to fire a slowing shot.
No, I like luck.
I like my luck.
That... no, we don't have time.
We don't have time.
No, thanks.
We go back and do it again.
Oh, that fucking creep.
Please die.
Get him out of here.
Kill him.
Oi, oi, oi.
Habits.
Recharges one bar of icing as an active item each time he takes damage.
That was unnecessary for me.
Can't just spawn a coin.
Honestly, I'm not thrilled.
Oh.
Plus five coins.
Doors and objects that normally require key tokens instead.
I don't need that.
Again.
Broken watch.
I like that one a lot.
We take that.
And this one, sharp luck using an uncharged item will exchange.
Half red heart for each missing charge segment.
No.
The ladder.
More range.
Shoot.
I'm good with that for now.
Keep moving.
So we got to start counting again.
What's that?
Smaller yet?
Sure.
Pretty soon we're going to get so small, no projectiles can hit us.
So how many was it?
Let's see here.
Every fourth room.
So we're at zero now.
One.
We don't need to do this right now, actually.
We're chilling.
Smaller yet?
Why not?
Dude, soon I can't see my character.
Legitimately a big problem, or a small problem, I mean.
No, wait.
How do I run into it every time?
Fuck.
I'm so bad.
There we go.
A snack.
Man, no deals for me.
Fuck.
It's okay.
Still behind the timer.
I think we may be cooked.
Let's see what the timer's in game.
Ninety, oh wait.
We got to go fast.
Hurry!
Speed!
Find the boss, find the boss.
Kill them all, kill them all.
Oh god.
No, we can't make it.
There's more.
Oh, you bastard.
I think we're cooked.
The speedrun dream is over.
But it's okay.
Oi!
Yo, yo, yo, yo, yo.
But wait a minute.
What's this?
Bloody recharge.
At least I revealed what it was.
It's okay.
I can't see my character, man.
I think the little ball is my character.
Oh, here, the boss was there!
Maybe I could have made it.
Maybe it's 21.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Sick.
More health.
And we get this.
A little brimstone.
Ooh, copies is good.
I like that one.
I could also go for the brimstone.
Copies the effect of...
Oh, that's cool.
Go down.
We're gonna nail this challenge.
When you give me bombs like that, I mean, come on.
Though we don't have to hurry anymore.
It's all Gucci.
You can chill.
Louse?
Small chance of spawning a blue spider anytime I see it in a room with enemies.
Nah.
I'm good.
We can potentially step here.
Already found a lot of HP.
Wait, door opened and we have a blue heart!
Ayy!
I think we're onto something with that.
It's all aligning.
Die, please.
One, two.
Beautiful.
Oh, this one's gonna be tough, isn't it?
Nicely aimed.
We go down.
Good stuff.
More speed.
Oh, it's a trinket.
I don't want that.
It's okay.
We're at one now.
Let me just find a blue heart there.
Oh, sick!
Secret for me.
Missing page two.
Yeah!
I gladly take that.
Wait, we just gained Devil Chance!
Okay.
Let's just write that down.
Attacking random enemy statue.
In secret room.
Devil Chance.
I don't know why that is doing that, like at all, but...
I'm gonna note it down.
I actually really like stopping the enemies in their tracks with the bomb.
If you aim it correctly, you can really be safe with it.
Feels good.
Should be looking for more secrets.
Okay, pop up.
The Emperor... nah.
Oh, shit.
Reset!
Should have used my card on that instead of my active.
Good stuff.
Watch this.
Hahaha!
Range up, okay.
Thank you, Shurn.
Oh, that's the boss.
Yeah, let's go.
Terratoma!
Dude, the bombs are going with the beast.
That was dope.
The belt is actually kind of cool, and we get to go in here as well.
I like it.
Guppy's tail, that makes this two out of three.
I can make it three out of three if I want to.
Fly though!
Guys, we take all three.
We take all three.
Uno, dos, tres.
This may have been a mistake.
I only have one red heart.
Fuck.
I gotta play well here.
This is a little questionable.
Nice.
Thank you very much.
Honestly, I'm slowly looking to replace this...
Oh, I can fly now.
Oh, I got spectral bombs.
Dude, I really need to reconfigure my brain now for this.
Pills galore.
We're going to do experimentation in here.
So wait, top right pill.
Nice!
Top left?
Whatever.
Bottom left?
I like it.
When entering a room with half a red heart or less, gain a little Steven Familiar.
I mean, we're almost at the point where this could be good.
But not yet.
I'm going to heal up here.
Show me the good stuff.
I could potentially step a little bit.
No, I'm not going to do it.
I need my blue hearts.
Let's go north.
Really, something is hiding in one of these.
I just messed up the bridge.
I mean, I can fly.
Contract from below.
Why not?
Was that worth it for the key?
I don't think it was.
I mean, now it is in hindsight, but I could have gone wrong.
Hold these flies.
Ah, man, I should have done that.
Okay, you know what?
This was bad.
Start that over.
Run it back.
We don't take the other chest.
Oh!
No!
Wait.
I accidentally clicked twice.
Fuck.
That was a mistake.
Hey, okay.
But now it's the old one, which is...
It doesn't tell me what the old one is.
Great.
I think it just slows the time in a room.
Yep, that's it.
Honestly, not...
Okay.
What?
No, my ad... my card...
You know what happened.
What a fucking...
beautiful catastrophe that just occurred.
I guess the series of unfortunate events.
Wow.
It lives.
And we're slowed.
We're slowing even more.
I wonder if it's gonna be mega-slowed now.
Really?
Well, son, you're gonna die hard now.
Bam.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
And there we go.
Let me actually just go in here and look.
I'm taking that.
I'm taking this.
Why the hell not?
And now we pick it up.
Not bad at all, huh?
The Chaos Card has appeared.
Beautiful way to end it, though.
Another challenge crossed off the list.
And we had some beautiful runs today.
I wanna say, I don't think we had a single, like, disastrous run.
This was all around solid.
You know, I had a couple runs where I got pretty far and I died.
You know, it is what it is.
But all in all, I'm happy with all of those.
That was great.
This was top one stream?
Really?
I don't think so.
I think the one where I broke the game was more fun.
But that's just me.
That's my opinion.
So far, that has been my favorite one.
Just because of the chaos of it.
But this one was great.
Another hush kill, yeah.
Dude!
Hush!
Zero.
Oliver, two.
That guy got nothing on me.
Wait, is it really 2-0?
Maybe it did find him in some other run and it lost.
I don't remember.
I think it's 2-0.
Yeah.
Okay.
Can you meow now?
No.
I will never meow meow, okay?
3-0 soon?
Wait, what is our win streak right now?
Let me see.
Oh, it's a minus one.
Nevermind, it's horrible.
Nevermind!
But yeah, I mean, the streak against hush is 2-0.
We're gonna make it 3-0 for sure.
The delirium fight was peak.
Yeah, I was so close, man!
I almost had that one!
Really curious to see what happened there if I actually made it.
Next time though, delirium is gonna fall.
I promise you.
Well, I promise you that I'm gonna do my best.
Legendary learning stream.
Hell yeah.
Right?
Some of those runs may not have been super successful, but I definitely learned a lot of new stuff.
And I unlocked more things, too.
You like Jacob's Ark?
Ooh, yeah.
Jacob's ladder was crazy.
Can you imagine Jacob's ladder on Azazel?
Huh?
Title of all, I love Jacob?
I was thinking of naming...
I actually had the idea halfway through what to name it.
I forgot what it was.
There was something I said.
What did I...
I said something very iconic and funny at one point.
Oh, yeah, Electroboom.
Something about Electroboom, because it was almost too perfect.
Electroboom is so niche.
Niche titles are funnier, though, in my opinion.
I think it's cooler if only one or two people get it.
What do you mean?
Electroboom is super popular.
Like, that guy has millions of subscribers.
What do you mean?
You will get times two views if you title it.
I love Jacob.
I don't know about that.
I mean, I have a pretty good idea of what titles get views, but I mean, maybe.
Maybe I'll...
Okay, here's what we're gonna do, guys.
We're gonna do an A-B test on YouTube, because I can do that with titles.
I'm gonna put, I love Jacob as one of them, and I love Electroboom as the other.
Or I am Electroboom, or something like that.
And then we're gonna see.
Huh?
Jacob's boobs?
Nah.
Electroboom is the boobs?
No, don't give me any tips.
I'll figure it out, Schmig.
Don't worry.
I'm relatively still early in the game, right?
I have a hundred hours so far, which is in Isaac, like, baby steps.
I'm gonna figure it out.
I won't click on it unless it says Jacob.
That's okay.
You don't have to click on it.
The Pentagon began to declassify a bunch of UFO files while you were streaming just now.
Okay, so they said, okay, here's a bunch of flying objects.
We don't know what is.
Cool.
I mean, all right.
It's just a bunch of flying objects, like, okay.
I would rather have them say, okay, guys, you're not gonna believe this shit.
We found aliens.
Here it is.
Here's a UFO flying.
You can see the lasers.
You can see the anti-gravity working.
Clear state.
HD 4K.
You know?
Then I'm in.
Then I'm like, okay.
Then I sit forward, like, that meme, you know?
Otherwise, I sleep.
If they actually say aliens confirmed, I go, real shit?
Then I'm in.
Call it, in this video, I obtained Jacob's ladder.
I'm guessing Jacob's ladder is, like, universally just considered an amazing item, then.
Because, I mean, I saw it immediately, right?
But that item is crazy.
We can all agree on that.
Tell me how you did your Red Dead cover art, I beg.
Well, aren't you lucky?
I put out a...
Hey, what do you call it?
A time-lapse video of me making it.
It's on my other channel.
More Oliver, is what it's called.
You can see it there.
Not insane, but good.
Well, that's your opinion.
I think it's crazy.
I'm just already imagining if I have, like, a lot of damage.
And I use the art lighting.
That would be nice.
I love Jacob.
Do you not get...
No, I don't get it.
No, don't spoil me anything.
Are you trying to spoil me, Loki, here?
Don't spoil me.
Didn't you work on very large baseline interferometry?
It wasn't my main area, but I did it as, like, a little side project.
I was cleaning up some data from some of that data, yeah.
It was a little exciting.
It wasn't that exciting, in the end, honestly.
But the idea behind it is always cool.
I just love the idea of, you know, combining telescopes that are thousands of kilometers apart.
And then, you know, doing the math behind that.
Or, I guess, computers do that nowadays.
But just the fact that you can do that is kind of blowing my mind.
Like, the precision you need, you need to know exactly how far apart these telescopes are, you know.
You need to know all of these things in huge detail.
It's just mind-blowing that we can do that stuff.
It's the same with adaptive optics.
I don't know if you've heard about that.
But some of those big telescopes have tiny motors on little segments of the mirror, right?
And they all individually move according to how the atmosphere is, you know, messing up the light waves coming in.
Or the waves, you know?
And it's just doing that in real time.
It's unbelievable.
Blows my mind, man.
So cool.
You haven't seen too many truly crazy items yet?
We'll see about that.
I feel like I've seen some pretty crazy shit.
I guess people must have their own opinions, right?
One person thinks X item is good, another person thinks Y item is good.
Of course there's got to be universally loved items and crazy items.
I'm excited to find more items.
Yeah, Data Miner is unbelievable.
Can we have more greed?
Yeah, sure.
I haven't seen Converter 2.
I think you're joking, but I hope you're not.
Oh, if there's a Converter 2,
then I know what's titled the video.
Guys, I gotta be really honest right now.
I really gotta go take a shit.
Like, I have some pretty bad gas.
I gotta end it here, man.
I'm like sweating.
Guys, thank you for watching.
This was a great session.
It's good to be back.
And I'll see you in the next video, okay?
Or stream.
Have a good night.
See ya.